9402 Spellman Ct. Las Vegas, NV 89123

(702) 301-3563

lakzhmysj@gmail.com lakzhmydsgn.editorx.io/portfolio

# LAKZHMY SAN JOSE

Industrial designer | materials and manufacturing enthusiast

My design philosophy derives from growing up in a country that endures daily exploitation of its rich landscapes and resilient communities. These formative experiences imbue my work with a sense of social responsibility. I believe that a deep understanding of the manufacturing process grounds the design of transformative products. My work takes a playful approach to integrating the material-conscious with the essential.

#### **DIGITAL TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite

Illustrator
Photoshop
InDesign
Premiere
Rhinoceros 3D
SolidWorks
Keyshot
Procreate

#### **FABRICATION SKILLS**

Foam Modeling
3D Printing
Laser Cutting
CNC Routing
Metal Casting
Welding & Brazing
Woodworking
Glass Blowing

#### **LANGUAGES**

English
Tagalog (Filipino)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Clayroom**, San Francisco Studio Assistant Intern

**Designed** and fabricated wooden tool shelves with budgeted materials **Manufactured** working mockups for wooden tools from limited resources **Interfaced** with diverse team to launch an operational woodworking studio

# Anthill Fabric Gallery, Cebu City, Philippines

Design Intern

Prepared iterative spec sheets for locally inspired gift card wallets

Designed educational hand loom mockups for touring studio guests

Proposed collection theme moodboards for submission to the Artefino Exhibit

## California College of the Arts, San Francisco

Rapid Prototypina Technician

IANUARY 2018 - MAY 2020

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019

JANUARY 2020

MARCH 2020 (studio suspended due to COVID-19)

**Converted** client 3D CAD files into the CNC routing programming language **Maintained** CNC routing machines by replacing and oiling specialized parts **Operated & Monitored** the CNC routing machine to produce a precise end product

**Constructed** cabinets with precise dimensions for the fashion department studios

### Soft Goods Lab Monitor

**Advised** proper methods of sewing and weaving for multistep project proposals **Optimized** sewing machines for ease of use by replacing and adjusting machine parts

Tool and Model Shop Assistant

AUGUST 2017 - DECEMBER 2019

**Collaborated** with clients to develop personalized tool and manufacturing sequences **Maintained** a diverse array of industrial machines at optimal working condition **Managed** efficient equipment operations in a studio prioritizing accident prevention

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Industrial Design California College of the Arts, San Francisco

MAY 2020